Vasiliy Demianets

Kharkiv, Kharkiv, Ukraine



vasiliy.demianets@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/vasiliy-demianets-825430148

Summary

"Bridging the gap between opportunity and expertise."

"Connecting the dots between careers and innovation."

"Building futures through technical placement."

As a seasoned technical recruiter, my work is driven by the belief that the right fit is instrumental in building a successful and productive team. Over the years, I have honed my skills in sourcing, assessing, and placing top talent within the tech sector. My passion for technology and talent acquisition enables me to connect high-caliber candidates with companies poised for growth.

Recently, I have also assumed the pivotal role of integrating Artificial Intelligence in recruitment processes, in collaboration with the Recruiting Innovation Office. By exploring, testing, and implementing Generative AI tools, I contribute to revolutionizing and optimizing recruitment strategies and operations. This alignment with cutting-edge technology further amplifies my ability to cater to clients' unique needs, cultures, and goals with precision and foresight.

I am committed to redefining the hiring landscape, assisting companies to reach their full potential through strategic technical recruitment and Al-powered process optimization.

Specializations:

- ★ Source, recruit, network, interview, and hire on the UA market and internationally;
- ★ Deep understanding of hiring processes, a dedication to continuous learning, adapting to the rapidly evolving tech industry, and a commitment to delivering exceptional results;
- ★ Account Management;
- ★ Automating and optimizing recruitment processes through AI;
- ★ Negotiation and Sales;
- ★ Mentoring/Learning Materials creation.

Experience



Senior Technical Recruiter

Brightgrove

Nov 2022 - Present (8 months)

Responsibilities:

- Global recruiting with a focus on Europe and Latin America;
- Account Management;
- Participating in pre-sale process and new client acquisition;
- Take part in internal talent allocations;
- Running internal recruitment and sourcing (sourcing strategy, tools, plugins, X-Ray, Linkedin search) knowledge sharing initiatives;

• Collaborating with the Recruiting Innovation Office to explore, test, and implement Generative AI tools to optimize recruitment strategies and operations.

BRIGHT

Technical Recruiter

Brightgrove

Mar 2021 - Nov 2022 (1 year 9 months)

Responsibilities:

- · Recruiting qualified candidates in Ukraine;
- Collecting vacancy requirements through effective questioning;
- Utilizing the candidate applicant tracking system as the primary tool and source;
- Networking to connect with relevant individuals for the job;
- Sourcing and recruiting the most suitable talent;
- Extending job offers that are difficult to decline;
- · Conducting market, skills, and salary research;
- Reporting progress and taking responsibility;
- Demonstrating initiative and suggesting process improvements;
- Collaborating with clients during the interview process;
- · Continuously learning and sharing knowledge with the team;
- Exploring and researching new recruiting tools and technology;
- · Sharing useful findings with the team.



Recruiter

Akvelon, Inc.

Jan 2019 - Mar 2021 (2 years 3 months)

Responsibilities:

Recruiting

- Manage the FLCR (Full Life Cycle Recruiting);
- Improving and seeking approaches to improve candidate experience, build strong collaborative relationships with hiring managers and recruitment team;
- Sourcing strategy planning and execution;
- Organization and participation in client interview preparation;
- Participate in career fairs and hackathons;
- Job Offers conditions presentation and negotiation;
- · Updating database and preparing reports.

Global Recruiting

- Was part of the recruitment team that launched the hiring process in the new regions;
- Conducting relocation process to USA (H1B/L1B visas);
- Market analysis.

HR

- · Onboarding of newcomers and further support;
- Organization of development internship programs;
- Assistance with internal candidate staffing for new project requests.



Lead Generation Manager

MWDN Ltd

Oct 2018 - Jan 2019 (4 months)

Responsibilities:

- Pre-sales activities:
- Searching for and attracting new customers from US/Israel markets through alternative channels;
- Negotiations with customers via LinkedIn, email, Skype etc;
- Forming the positive image of the company and being in touch with potential clients;
- · Managing corporate CRM;
- · Launch and support internal sales wiki;
- · Monitoring tasks performance statistics

Recruitment Researcher

MWDN Ltd

Jul 2018 - Oct 2018 (4 months)

Responsibilities:

- Searching of candidates using all possible sources;
- Screening candidates;
- Updating database with required information;
- Formatting CV;
- · Preparing reports;
- Interviews with candidates (phone, skype)

Education



Yaroslav Mudryi National Law University

Bachelor's degree, Law 2017 - 2021



H. S. Skovoroda Kharkiv National Pedagogical University

BS, Economics and Management

2021 - Present

Licenses & Certifications

oo English - Duolingo



- in Writing to be Heard on LinkedIn LinkedIn
- in Professional Networking LinkedIn
- in Sales: Closing Strategies LinkedIn

- in Strategic Human Resources LinkedIn
- in Recruiting Foundations LinkedIn
- HR Recruiting Communication Strategies to Attract and Retain Top Talent LinkedIn

Skills

Recruiting • Networking • Sourcing • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Account Management • Business Development • Sales • Research • Screening Resumes • Pre-sales